# **Daniel Kim**

Sydney, New South Wales, Australia



in linkedin.com/in/daniel-kim-dk



dcsk.daniel@gmail.com



0467331689

## Summary

An excellent attitude towards life, the workplace and relationships. Understanding of cultural diversities.

\*\*Currently acquiring a new skill in IT (diploma) as a Full-stack Developer. Specialising in Ruby, Java, jS, HTML/CSS, ruby rails, Mongo.db, python. \*\*\*

I view myself as a coachable, easy going, passionate individual - particularly within manufacturing, whether it may be the humble paper clip, to mega mechanical structure's, I'm fascinated by it all - I consistently strive to implement new method's from current and traditional norm's and hope to acheive this through innovative, ethical, and sustainable advancements that'll benefit the future of this industry.

My backround always has been, tech-related, even as a child with a wonder and curiosity towards how 'things' work - within nature, and man made - inevitably leading me down the route of studying STEM subjects from highschool through to University.

I strongly beleive, with mentorship and training, I will flourish and be a valuable investment to whomever that shares the same vision.

I'm always hungry to learn!

# **Experience**

#### Barista

The Grounds

Mar 2019 - Present (1 year 2 months +)

- \* Servicing customers with specialty coffee. Geisha washed beans, dose/extraction control espresso's, Cold drip, Percolated coffee.
- \* 15+ kilos per day.



## Volunteer

HyperPower Technologies

2017 - Present (3 years 4 months +)

- \* In-house machinist, from initial design, to proof of concept, to prototyping.
- \* Working under the guidance and mentorship of the CTO.

# Sales Executive

### SINI AUSTRALIA PTY LTD

Feb 2018 - Nov 2018 (10 months)

- \* B2B wholesale for locally manufactured cosmetic goods.
- \* Opened 17 new accounts within the first 3 months of role.
- \* Improved customer relations with business objectives.



# Head of Manufacturing | ECU-R

**Edith Cowan University** 

Jan 2014 - Feb 2018 (4 years 2 months)

- \* Machined custom designed, high precision components out of 4140 steel, 6061 aluminium, brass and plastics. (Colchester's).
- \* Oversee the production and timeline of manufacturing of parts for race car, utilising team resources.
- \* Organising training of use of machines, setting deadlines for task completion.

Maintaining strict quality control measures.

\* Examples of the types of parts made are: planetary gear case housings for steering systems, suspension uprights, aerodynamic pedo tubes for measuring air pressure, various size bearing housings, wing brackets, many many spacers for all sorts of gaps, hole boring - all sizes, modifications to drive shafts and dog gears, custom sized bolts, I have also worked with composites, such as carbon/kevlar, epoxies, aluminium honeycomb and structural foam. Using vacuum bagging techniques with the composites to create parts, experienced in TIG/MIG welding of steel.



# Mechatronics Engineer

Top EV Racing

Jul 2015 - Dec 2017 (2 years 6 months)

\* Volunteer role acting as the Junior Mechatronics engineer, applying university knowledge of race car science to assist with the development of high performance electric vehicles powered through renewable energy sources.



# Bar Attendant/ Customer Service

Crown Resorts

Oct 2010 - Apr 2017 (6 years 7 months)

## **Education**



## Coder Academy

Full-stack Developer

2020 - Present

Ruby, HTML/CSS, ruby rails, Javascript, Node js, React, Mongo DB, Express js



### Edith Cowan University

Bachelor of Engineering (B.Eng.), Mechatronics and Motorsports Engineering 2014 - 2018



## **Central Institute of Technology**

Advance Diploma in Mechancial, Mechanical Engineering 2011 - 2013



# Central Institute of Technology

Diploma in Mechanical CAD, Mechanical Engineering 2010 - 2011



### Kingsway Christian College

Science and Technology 1999 - 2008

### Skills

Automotive • NC Machining • SolidWorks CAD • Customer Satisfaction • Customer Service • Ruby • Java • HTML • Python (Programming Language) • MongoDB